All right guys and welcome to day two of the Attraction Blueprint
Hola a todos y bienvenidos al segundo día del programa "Plan de Atracción".
and we're going to add another level to confidence today and
Hoy fortaleceremos su autoestima y
we're going to talk about having a growth mindset and active reframing.
nos centraremos en una mentalidad de crecimiento y un replanteamiento activo.
The reason these two things are so important is guys hate to break it to you,
Estos dos elementos son esenciales porque, aunque los hombres se resistan a admitirlo,
but you live in the real world with real objections, real rejections and real people.
viven en el mundo real, con objeciones reales, rechazos reales y personas reales.
Nothing's linear and lot of mistakes that guys make is they think there's
Nada es simple, y muchos hombres cometen el error de creer que hay
like this just five-step plan of success and I'm sorry that's just not how...
un camino fácil al éxito. Lo siento, pero no funciona así.
this works, so what I want to give you today is a couple tools
Hoy quiero darles herramientas para
to help you just build upon your confidence in a more active way,
su autoestima
in a more like internal way where you can,
fortalecer activa e internamente
tell better stories and reframe things that happen to you,
, para contar su historia con mayor eficacia y para reinterpretar los eventos que les suceden.
so you're becoming stronger through this process,
Saldrán fortalecidos,
you're becoming better through this process and not letting things drag you down,
evolucionarán y nunca más se dejarán vencer.
not letting things beat you up,
El
so the first thing I want to talk about is the power of story,
primer punto que quiero abordar es el poder de las historias.
when we are out in the real world, we're talking to women when we're having conversations,
En la vida cotidiana, ya sea en conversaciones con mujeres o
we're interacting with anyone, we're constantly creating internal stories,
con otras personas, creamos constantemente narrativas internas.
and the cool thing about that is you are the creator of those stories,
Y lo más interesante es que ustedes son los creadores de estas narrativas.
so the question to then ask yourself is how
Así que la pregunta que deben hacerse es: ¿Qué
much power do I have in the creation of that story,
poder tengo para dar forma a estas historias?
am I letting the world tell me my story,
¿Dejo que el mundo me dicte lo que hago? ¿
am I letting my failures create story, am I letting my rejections create that story,
Dejo que mis errores, mis rechazos
or am I tak this upon myself and saying no,
o... me definan? ¿O asumo la responsabilidad y digo: «No,
I'm the creator, I actually create these stories and I'm going to write a better story.
soy la creadora, yo doy forma a estas historias y voy a escribir una mejor»?
Yeah, I might have failed in the past.
Sí, puede que haya fracasado en el pasado.
Yeah, I might have had some problems, but you know what,
Sí, puede que haya tenido problemas, pero ¿sabes qué?
I don't have to be that person, the past is the past.
No tengo por qué seguir así. El pasado es el pasado.
It's called that for a reason i can now today decide to make and create better story,
Se llama así por algo. Hoy puedo elegir escribir una mejor historia.
so you have that free will, and I love um,
Tienes ese libre albedrío. Y me encanta
great book by Victor Frankel, um, man search for meaning talks about the real power.
el libro de Viktor Frankl, «La vida en busca del sentido», que describe el verdadero poder que
have is in the separation between stimulus and response,
reside en separar el estímulo de la respuesta.
that space there between stimulus and how you respond to that stimulus,
Ese espacio entre el estímulo y tu respuesta
that is actually your free will and that is your space to create story.
es tu libre albedrío, tu espacio para crear historias.
this is super powerful, especially when deal with women,
Es increíblemente poderoso, especialmente para las mujeres,
because let's be honest, they will be the biggest trigger in your life,
porque, seamos sinceras, a menudo son la principal fuente de reacciones negativas en tu vida.
so the more space you can create there between stimulus and response,
Cuanto más espacio crees entre el estímulo y la respuesta,
the more power you then have to write a better story, so lot of...
más poder tendrás para contar una historia más positiva. Mucha gente
when they hear this though, they're going to think affirmations and positive self talk,
piensa en las afirmaciones y el diálogo interno positivo en este contexto.
look, all that is powerful for the right person,
Claro que todo esto puede ser efectivo para la persona adecuada,
it is called personal development for a reason, it's highly personal,
y hay una razón por la que hablamos de desarrollo personal: es un asunto muy individual.
but what i like to do is say, okay, who do i want to be, what story i want to write,
Personalmente, sin embargo, me gusta preguntarme: "¿Quién quiero ser? ¿Qué historia quiero escribir?".
but more importantly, and this is part of this whole equation,
Pero sobre todo —y esto es crucial—,
is what identity do i want to create for myself,
¿qué identidad quiero crear para mí?
and it's not about faking it to you make it,
No se trata de fingir;
it's literally about who do i want to be in this world, okay?
se trata de saber realmente quién quiero ser en este mundo.
in order to be that person, must take on that identity,
Para ser esa persona, tienes que aceptar esa identidad.
because without getting like too deep in the rabbit hole guys,
Porque, sin enredarme en consideraciones complejas,
who you are as an identity dictates the actions you take, right?
tu identidad determina tus acciones, ¿no?
like if you are the identity of,
Si tu identidad es, por ejemplo, "
hey, i have amazing conversation skills and i'm absolutely great with women,
Tengo talento para la conversación y me siento muy cómodo en compañía de mujeres", entonces
you're going to take actions from that identity,
actuarás en consecuencia.
so when i think about like positive self-talk affirmations,
Así que, cuando pienso en afirmaciones positivas para mi diálogo interno,
i'm to me thinking about creating a stronger identity,
mi objetivo es fortalecer mi identidad.
this for myself and it's going to sound cheesy but it is what it is like before
Puede
i would go a date and before i would go talk to him like man she's so lucky that i'm
parecer un poco trillado, pero así es como me siento antes de una cita, antes de acercarme a ella: "Qué suerte tiene de que pueda
going to go talk to her right now because i'm an absolute gift right i'm i'm the man
hablar con ella ahora, porque soy el hombre auténtico, el hombre
she desires to be with so the fact i'm going to talk to her she's incredibly lucky
que tanto anhelaba". El solo hecho de poder hablar con ella la hace increíblemente feliz.
right now that's the identity that i would take on before i would go talk to her
Adopto esta mentalidad antes de acercarme a ella
cause it would put me a state of abundance it would put me a really powerful
porque me pone en un estado de abundancia, una
um mindset so that's kind of what i want to talk to you about today is like what
forma de pensar realmente poderosa. De esto es precisamente de lo que quiero hablarte hoy: ¿qué
identity do you want to have?
identidad quieres tener?
that goes and talks to women and putting yourself in that identity right,
Se trata de iniciar conversaciones con mujeres e identificarte con ellas diciéndote
like just talking yourself like, hey, i am this person,
: "Soy esta persona,
i'm not the kind of person that thinks this way, no, i am this person.
no soy de las que piensan así, no, soy esta persona".
um, step two today guys is active reframing through my health journey,
El segundo paso de hoy es el replanteamiento activo. Gracias a mi experiencia en el sector sanitario y
through my coaching practice, this is probably the you know most powerful,
a mi práctica como coach, esto es probablemente lo
most powerful thing that ever learned how to do,
más efectivo que he aprendido.
um, and even with my clients, i like i said, i coach lot of high performance clients too,
Incluso para mis clientes (como ya he dicho, coacheo a muchos clientes muy exitosos),
active reframing is one of the most powerful
el replanteamiento activo es una de las técnicas más efectivas
things you learn how to do in this world of growth,
de desarrollo personal.
so here's what it is, active reframing is something happens,
El replanteamiento activo significa preguntarse
how do i want to reframe what just happened right?
cómo puedes evaluar tu experiencia actual de forma diferente.
this really easy example of that is let's say a girl turns down,
Un ejemplo sencillo: una chica te rechaza. Podrías
she rejects you, okay, you could one frame could be,
pensar: "
oh man, i'm a loser, she rejected me, i'm not good enough, or you could reframe that like,
Ay, no, soy un fracaso, me rechazó, no soy lo suficientemente bueno". O podrías pensar: "
okay, cool, i guess i'm just not her type, how can i get better?
Bueno, vale, supongo que no soy su tipo. ¿Qué puedo hacer?".
okay, she obviously like didn't like something i said, maybe we should vibe,
Obviamente, no le gustó algo que dije. Quizás deberíamos intentar entendernos.
maybe you know we're just on two different planes, whatever,
Quizás simplemente estamos en sintonía.
how could i get better from this, like what can i say differently,
Entonces, ¿cómo puedo mejorar? ¿Qué puedo decir diferente?
what can do differently next time, it's not me person
¿Qué puedo hacer diferente la próxima vez? No se trata de mí
personally is just maybe something just what in alignment right?
personalmente; podría ser simplemente una cuestión de alineación interna.
i'm going to look at the things that happen in my life that stimulus creates space
Analizaré lo que está sucediendo en mi vida: cómo un estímulo
between response and in that space i'm going to reframe that in a way that's going
crea una brecha entre la respuesta y la situación. Y en ese momento, replantearé la situación de una manera que me permita
to make me a better person do and believe what makes you better so i'm going
crecer. Haz y cree en lo que te ayuda a evolucionar. Luego miraré
to reframe what just happened in a positive way and say okay what you're right
lo sucedido desde una perspectiva positiva y me diré: "Vale, tienes razón,
didn't say this right i should have said this i should ask this question maybe
no dije eso. Debería haber dicho eso. Debería haber hecho esa pregunta.
i shouldn't have talked so much.
Quizás debería haber dicho menos". Quizás
Maybe I should have been more in a state of curiosity,
debería haber sido más curioso...
um, so I'm going to actively reframe that
Por lo tanto, replantearé activamente esta
situation to put myself in a better position moving forward,
situación para posicionarme mejor para el futuro.
so that is what I want you to practice this week,
Esto es exactamente lo que quiero que practiques esta semana en tus interacciones con los demás
in your interactions with people, as you're out there playing the compliment game,
. Cuando hagas cumplidos,
before you go and give the compliment, I want you to actively put in a new identity,
quiero que adoptes activamente una nueva identidad antes de decir uno.
all right, so what identity do I want to have,
¿Qué identidad quiero tener? ¿
who do I want to be, how do I want to show up before?
Quién quiero ser? ¿Cómo quiero presentarme?
you will give that compliment and then if something negative happens,
Darás el cumplido, y si ocurre algo negativo,
you actively reframe it in that moment,
lo replantearás activamente en ese momento,
not later when you're journaling, that's what's called active reframing,
no más tarde en tu diario. Esto se llama replanteamiento activo:
you're going to reframe it in that moment and say,
lo replantearás inmediatamente y te dirás a ti mismo:
oh you know what, it's cool, like I learned this,
"Oye, genial, aprendí de esto..."
um, next, I you should teach lot of sales,
. Deberías impartir muchos cursos de ventas.
and when I was teaching sales, I would tell guys,
Cuando impartía cursos de ventas, siempre decía: "Un '
no just means next, right, yes, you want to get better from no,
no' simplemente significa 'Sigamos adelante'". Sí, después de un "no", quieres seguir adelante,
but let's actively reframe no to next,
pero reformulemos activamente ese "no" como "Sigamos adelante".
right, okay, so I got rejection, how do I take that, get better from it,
Bien, me han rechazado, ¿cómo lo manejo? ¿Qué puedo aprender de esto?
all right, moving on, that does that no longer bothers me,
Sigamos adelante. Ya no me molesta;
it was a is a great learning lesson.
ha sido una lección valiosa.
okay, so that's the challenge I want to give you for today is active reframing,
Este es el reto que les propongo hoy: Replanteamiento Activo.
when that self-doubt appears, when that insecurity appears,
En cuanto surja la duda, la incertidumbre,
when you have any type of negative thought come into your brain,
un pensamiento negativo, transfórmalo
reframe it and then take action.
y actúa.
action from day one I told you, action is the most important thing right,
Como dije desde el principio, la acción es crucial,
because nothing happens without action,
porque sin ella, nada sucede.
so how can I create new identity actively reframe to?
Entonces, ¿cómo puedo crear una nueva identidad reposicionándome activamente? ¿Cómo puedo
keep myself in a positive momentum, keep myself positively moving forward,
mantener un impulso positivo y avanzar con entusiasmo?
that's it for today guys, hope you got something out of it, leave us some comments,
Eso es todo por hoy. Espero que les haya sido útil. Déjennos un comentario y
let us know how this new identity and this active reframing is working for you guys,
cuéntennos cómo les está funcionando esta nueva identidad y este replanteamiento activo.
we love hearing your feedback in the community and for day three tomorrow we're
Agradecemos sus comentarios en la comunidad. Mañana, tercer día,
going to talk about energy priming because lik
hablaremos de la preparación energética porque, como
e we talked about yesterday she feels energy,
dijimos ayer, se siente la energía.
energy is the most important thing that you can possibly transfer to her,
La energía es lo más importante que podemos darles.
so tomorrow we're going to get into energy priming,
Por eso, mañana nos centraremos en la preparación energética.
i just need you in the right mindset before we could do a little bit energy work,
Solo necesito que estén en el estado de ánimo adecuado antes de comenzar este trabajo energético.
so guys, hope you got something out of it,
Eso es todo. Espero que les haya sido útil.
thank you so much for tuning in and I'll see you tomorrow.
¡Gracias por leer y nos vemos mañana!